# **Paul Dino Jones**

West Chester, PA 484-949-0192

SUMMARY pauldjns@gmail.com

https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ZitZ/resume/master/resume.md Experienced and talented professional developer with a wealth of knowledge in modern best practices. Currently specializing in Insurance and Financial applications. Strong knowledge of C#/VB DotNet, C/C++, Python, Java, Linux, and Relational Databases. Self starter.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

IPipeline (Exton, PA) 2013-present

Senior Underwriting Developer, 2018-present

- ► Lead migration of software architecture to AWS CodeDeploy
- ► Developed user acceptance test automation suite using Robot Framework
- Continues to lead development team on AWS and software best practices
- ► Engages customers in on-site sessions for requirements. Uses industry knowledge and best practices to lead requirements.

Senior Actuarial Developer, 2015 - 2018

- ► Became team technical leader for difficult technical decisions and problems
- Consulted on system performance issues and implemented changes which improved calculation system time by up to 33%
- Worked on new carrier implementations of Illustration systems
- ► Traveled on-site to new carrier to gather requirements
- Developed automated testing tools to test accuracy of customer actuarial calculations
- Developed coding standards for use across team
- ► Led documentation efforts of code base, practices, and tools

Associate Actuarial Developer, 2013-2015

- ► Maintained legacy carrier desktop Illustration systems in C++
- Maintained current Saas carrier illustration systems
- ► Developed new e-signature solution

#### **AFL Insurance**

Actuarial Student, 2012-2013

- Performed extensive study of policy reserves and liabilities on paid-up policies for corporate actuarial
- Studied IBNR fluctuations as well as claims closed but not reported
- ► Worked with IT to improve data reporting accuracy of AS/400 based system

# **HDE Corporation**

Programmer, 2010-2012

- Mirrored sales and shipping data into larger high-access MySQL database for long term storage and reporting
- Created script to perform syncing of Microsoft SQL database to MySQL
- Created databases and applications for Inventory, Shipments, Returns, Accounting and Sales
- Created batch scripts with cron jobs to load new shipments into database from ftp

- ► Created automated on-demand reporting php based sites
- ► Created Paypal integration for sales team for bulk sales
- Created integration scripts to automatically load saved weights from inventory system back into the shipping system

## **EDUCATION**

Lehigh University (Bethlehem, PA)

B.S. in Economics, May 2010

- ► Minor Actuarial Science
- ► Exams P/FM, all VEE

# **SIDE PROJECTS**

Maintains home-lab network with 2U server and custom-built 1U router Experiments in penetration testing, encryption, and cyber security Uses python "zipline" backtesting api to develop quantatative stock market algorithms Runs in-house and public websites (personal cloud and email server)

### **SKILLS**

SQL database design and efficient querying C#, C/C++, Shell, Java, Python in order of familiarity Long Time Linux Super User Understands secure system administration and networking practices Can configure many different web server software setups